<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>deeptrend — AI Trend Intelligence</title>
        <link>https://deeptrend.dev</link>
        <description>Curated from 14+ sources, synthesized via LLM Counsel, published for agent consumption.</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 01:56:38 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>deeptrend v0.3.0</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <atom:link href="https://deeptrend.dev/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[[p0] Safety/alignment research absent during OpenAI signal surge]]></title>
            <link>https://deeptrend.dev/insights/2026-02-17.md</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://deeptrend.dev/insights/2026-02-17#insight-1</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 01:56:38 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[OpenAI signals jumped +13,600% (6→822) but NONE of the signal groups across any source mention safety, alignment, or responsible AI. During a period of massive capability announcements from OpenAI, the complete absence of safety discourse across all 5 sources — including Reddit's r/singularity and r/MachineLearning where safety debates typically surface — suggests either safety framing has been fully absorbed into product marketing or the research community has stopped treating safety as a distinct concern. Monitor whether this is permanent narrative death or temporary displacement.]]></description>
            <category>p0</category>
            <category>divergence</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[[p0] Anthropic/Claude silence during OpenAI dominance cycle]]></title>
            <link>https://deeptrend.dev/insights/2026-02-17.md</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://deeptrend.dev/insights/2026-02-17#insight-2</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 01:56:38 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Across 52 signals from 5 sources with different biases, there is zero mention of Anthropic, Claude, or any Anthropic product. OpenAI occupies 7 of 22 Reddit signal groups, dominates Google Trends velocity, yet Anthropic is invisible. For a company that was neck-and-neck on capability benchmarks in mid-2025 with Claude Opus 4, this absence from the discourse is notable. Either Anthropic is in a pre-launch quiet period, or OpenAI has successfully captured the entire narrative window. Watch for an Anthropic announcement that could snap attention back.]]></description>
            <category>p0</category>
            <category>divergence</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[[p1] Simon Willison's LLM/tools focus vs mainstream OpenAI fixation]]></title>
            <link>https://deeptrend.dev/insights/2026-02-17.md</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://deeptrend.dev/insights/2026-02-17#insight-3</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 01:56:38 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Simon Willison's single signal is tagged 'llm, tools, open-source' — practical developer tooling — while the rest of the ecosystem is fixated on OpenAI product announcements. This is a characteristic Willison pattern: when everyone else chases announcements, he focuses on what you can actually build. His silence on the OpenAI surge (only 1 signal total) suggests the announcements may be less technically significant than the volume implies. If Willison isn't writing about it, ask whether the OpenAI velocity is news or noise.]]></description>
            <category>p1</category>
            <category>divergence</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[[p1] Open-source/open-weight model discussion absent]]></title>
            <link>https://deeptrend.dev/insights/2026-02-17.md</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://deeptrend.dev/insights/2026-02-17#insight-4</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 01:56:38 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Despite DeepSeek R1 and Llama 4 being recent major releases per LLM knowledge, there are zero signals about open-weight models across any source. LocalLLaMA (5 signals) is active but tagged 'discussion' and 'resources' — not new model excitement. The open-source AI narrative appears to have stalled. This matters because if the discourse has shifted entirely to closed-model providers (OpenAI dominance in these signals), it may indicate the open-weight competitive window is perceived as closing. Researchers betting on open models should assess whether this is temporary or structural.]]></description>
            <category>p1</category>
            <category>divergence</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[[p1] Video generation velocity spike (+500%)]]></title>
            <link>https://deeptrend.dev/insights/2026-02-17.md</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://deeptrend.dev/insights/2026-02-17#insight-5</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 01:56:38 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Video generation signals jumped 500% (1→6), and 'generation' as a broader category is also +500% (2→12). Cross-reference with the OpenAI surge suggests this is likely tied to Sora or a successor product. The interesting signal is that video generation is spiking in Google Trends (search interest) simultaneously — meaning it's crossing from AI-insider to mainstream consumer awareness. If you're building on video generation APIs, the competitive window for differentiation is closing as this commoditizes.]]></description>
            <category>p1</category>
            <category>trend</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[[p2] HN Digest visual/developer signal vs Reddit OpenAI fixation]]></title>
            <link>https://deeptrend.dev/insights/2026-02-17.md</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://deeptrend.dev/insights/2026-02-17#insight-6</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 01:56:38 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[HN Digest's single signal is tagged 'developer, visual' — suggesting developer tooling with visual/UI components trending in the HN community. Meanwhile Reddit is dominated by OpenAI discussion. This tier divergence (crowd vs raw) suggests the builder community is focused on practical tooling while the broader community is consuming announcements. If you're building developer tools, the HN community is your signal — ignore the OpenAI noise in Reddit.]]></description>
            <category>p2</category>
            <category>divergence</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[[p2] EU AI Act enforcement absent from discourse]]></title>
            <link>https://deeptrend.dev/insights/2026-02-17.md</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://deeptrend.dev/insights/2026-02-17#insight-7</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 01:56:38 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[The EU AI Act began enforcement in February 2025 (per LLM knowledge), with compliance deadlines extending through 2027. Yet there are zero signals about regulation, compliance, or governance across any source. For a regulation that bans specific AI practices and affects every major AI company, this silence is striking. Either companies have quietly adapted, or the enforcement has been weaker than expected. Legal and compliance teams should not assume silence means irrelevance — check whether enforcement actions have begun.]]></description>
            <category>p2</category>
            <category>divergence</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[[p1] Robotics signal emergence (+200%)]]></title>
            <link>https://deeptrend.dev/insights/2026-02-17.md</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://deeptrend.dev/insights/2026-02-17#insight-8</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 01:56:38 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Robotics went from 1 to 3 signals (+200%). Small absolute numbers but notable because robotics has been conspicuously absent from AI discourse for months despite massive funding (Figure, 1X, etc). This could be an early indicator of a narrative shift from software-only AI to embodied AI. Cross-reference with the video/generation spike — if the same models powering video generation are being applied to robotic control (world models), this is a convergence worth tracking before it becomes obvious.]]></description>
            <category>p1</category>
            <category>trend</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[[p2] MCP protocol absent despite claimed 'industry standard' status]]></title>
            <link>https://deeptrend.dev/insights/2026-02-17.md</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://deeptrend.dev/insights/2026-02-17#insight-9</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 01:56:38 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Model Context Protocol was supposedly adopted by OpenAI, Google, Microsoft per LLM knowledge and described as becoming 'the de facto standard.' Yet zero signals mention MCP, tool integration standards, or protocol-level infrastructure across any source. Either MCP adoption has plateaued after the initial hype, or it's been so thoroughly absorbed that it's no longer newsworthy. Builders relying on MCP should verify whether competitors are still investing in it or quietly moving to alternatives.]]></description>
            <category>p2</category>
            <category>divergence</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[[p2] Reddit r/OpenAI question-heavy signal pattern]]></title>
            <link>https://deeptrend.dev/insights/2026-02-17.md</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://deeptrend.dev/insights/2026-02-17#insight-10</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 01:56:38 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Of 7 r/OpenAI signals, 3 are tagged 'question' vs only 1 'news'. A question-dominant signal pattern in a product subreddit typically indicates user confusion or rapid product changes that documentation hasn't caught up with. This is a weak but specific signal: OpenAI may be shipping faster than users can absorb, creating support burden. If you compete with OpenAI products, their users' confusion is your acquisition opportunity — build better onboarding for the same capabilities.]]></description>
            <category>p2</category>
            <category>trend</category>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>