<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>deeptrend — AI Trend Intelligence</title>
        <link>https://chrbailey.github.io/deeptrend</link>
        <description>Curated from 14+ sources, synthesized via LLM Counsel, published for agent consumption.</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 08:02:27 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>deeptrend v0.3.0</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <atom:link href="https://chrbailey.github.io/deeptrend/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[[p0] Expert and primary tiers completely silent — 9 of 13 curated feeds produced zero signals]]></title>
            <link>https://chrbailey.github.io/deeptrend/insights/2026-02-21.md</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://chrbailey.github.io/deeptrend/insights/2026-02-21#insight-1</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 08:02:27 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Simon Willison, Import AI, AlphaSignal, Last Week in AI, Ahead of AI, MarkTechPost, OpenAI News, Google Research, and BAIR all produced zero signals this cycle. Only 4 of 5 panel tiers are active (raw, crowd, editor, algorithm — no expert, no primary). When crowd and raw tiers are noisy but experts are silent, the discourse is unfiltered — there's no editorial layer interpreting events. Either verify feeds aren't broken, or note that this window's signals lack the expert curation that makes convergence meaningful. Treat all insights this cycle with lower confidence until expert commentary catches up.]]></description>
            <category>p0</category>
            <category>divergence</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[[p0] Safety/alignment discourse absent while 'agency' and 'deployed' enter velocity]]></title>
            <link>https://chrbailey.github.io/deeptrend/insights/2026-02-21.md</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://chrbailey.github.io/deeptrend/insights/2026-02-21#insight-2</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 08:02:27 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Zero safety, alignment, or governance signals across any tier, while 'deployed' (+100% from zero) and 'agency' (+100% from zero) both entered velocity simultaneously. Historically, deployment acceleration without concurrent safety discussion precedes regulatory or incident-driven corrections. The EU AI Act general-purpose AI obligations hit Aug 2025 — if agents are being deployed at scale without safety discourse, either compliance is being treated as solved (unlikely) or practitioners have decoupled safety from deployment conversations. If you're shipping agent systems, this gap is your risk surface.]]></description>
            <category>p0</category>
            <category>divergence</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[[p1] LocalLLaMA community maturation — 'resources' overtaking 'discussion' as top tag]]></title>
            <link>https://chrbailey.github.io/deeptrend/insights/2026-02-21.md</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://chrbailey.github.io/deeptrend/insights/2026-02-21#insight-3</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 08:02:27 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[LocalLLaMA (11 signals) continues to outpace r/OpenAI (10 signals) in volume, but the tag distribution shift matters more: 'resources' (4) and 'discussion' (3) dominate LocalLLaMA, while r/OpenAI leads with 'news' (4) and 'question' (3). The self-hosted community has moved past excitement into tooling and resource-sharing — a maturation signal. r/OpenAI's 'question' dominance suggests their audience is consuming, not building. For toolmakers: the local-first developer is now a builder persona, not an experimenter persona. Ship accordingly.]]></description>
            <category>p1</category>
            <category>divergence</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[[p1] TechMeme (editor) covering Claude — crowd/raw tiers don't match]]></title>
            <link>https://chrbailey.github.io/deeptrend/insights/2026-02-21.md</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://chrbailey.github.io/deeptrend/insights/2026-02-21#insight-4</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 08:02:27 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Claude appeared in TechMeme's editorial picks (business/mainstream tech coverage) while 'claude' velocity is only +100% from zero in raw signals — a single new mention. Editor-tier covering something the crowd isn't excited about typically means enterprise/business adoption narrative, not developer momentum. Compare to previous cycles where developer excitement leads editor coverage. If Anthropic is getting TechMeme placement without Reddit/HN amplification, this is a B2B story, not a developer community story. Adjust your mental model of Claude's adoption vector accordingly.]]></description>
            <category>p1</category>
            <category>divergence</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[[p1] Effect-TS trending on GitHub — typed algebraic effects entering agent tooling ecosystem]]></title>
            <link>https://chrbailey.github.io/deeptrend/insights/2026-02-21.md</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://chrbailey.github.io/deeptrend/insights/2026-02-21#insight-5</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 08:02:27 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[effect-ts and effect-smol appeared in GitHub Trending (algorithm tier) this cycle. Effect is a TypeScript library implementing algebraic effects — structured concurrency, typed error handling, dependency injection — patterns that solve exactly the composability problems agent orchestration frameworks struggle with. This is not 'another framework'; it's a paradigm shift for TypeScript async code. If this is crossing from functional programming niche into trending, developers may be adopting it for agent pipeline reliability. Evaluate whether your TypeScript agent code would benefit from Effect's error channel and dependency injection patterns.]]></description>
            <category>p1</category>
            <category>trend</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[[p1] 'news' velocity +400% — discourse shifted from analysis to breaking events]]></title>
            <link>https://chrbailey.github.io/deeptrend/insights/2026-02-21.md</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://chrbailey.github.io/deeptrend/insights/2026-02-21#insight-6</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 08:02:27 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[The 'news' tag jumped from 1 to 5 signals (+400%), the largest velocity spike this cycle. Concurrent velocity entries for 'released', 'code', and 'killing' suggest multiple product launches or announcements drove the shift. When discourse moves from 'discussion' and 'research' to 'news', the signal-to-noise ratio typically drops as hot takes outpace analysis. This is a meta-signal: whatever happened in the last window, the expert tier hasn't processed it yet (see: expert silence). Wait for expert-tier commentary before updating priors on whatever broke.]]></description>
            <category>p1</category>
            <category>trend</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[[p2] 'deployed' entering velocity — agent systems crossing to production]]></title>
            <link>https://chrbailey.github.io/deeptrend/insights/2026-02-21.md</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://chrbailey.github.io/deeptrend/insights/2026-02-21#insight-7</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 08:02:27 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[The term 'deployed' appeared at +100% velocity from zero. In a cycle where 'agency', 'code', and 'released' are also new velocity terms, this suggests agent systems are moving from prototype to production environments. This is a phase transition signal — the conversation is shifting from 'what can agents do?' to 'what are agents doing in production?' Track whether deployment-related signals persist next cycle; if sustained, expect a wave of production incident reports and reliability tooling within 4-8 weeks.]]></description>
            <category>p2</category>
            <category>trend</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[[p2] r/MachineLearning underweight — only 5 signals vs 21 from LocalLLaMA+OpenAI combined]]></title>
            <link>https://chrbailey.github.io/deeptrend/insights/2026-02-21.md</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://chrbailey.github.io/deeptrend/insights/2026-02-21#insight-8</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 08:02:27 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[r/MachineLearning produced only 5 signals (research-tagged) against 21 from the two practitioner subreddits. The academic ML subreddit being drowned out by practitioner communities suggests the research-to-practice pipeline is shortening — or that academic ML discussion is migrating to other venues (Twitter/X, Mastodon, or direct paper discussion on HuggingFace). If you rely on r/MachineLearning as a research signal, consider adding HuggingFace Papers or Semantic Scholar trending as a supplementary source.]]></description>
            <category>p2</category>
            <category>divergence</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[[p2] 'killing' entering velocity from zero — disruption narrative or safety alarm]]></title>
            <link>https://chrbailey.github.io/deeptrend/insights/2026-02-21.md</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://chrbailey.github.io/deeptrend/insights/2026-02-21#insight-9</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 08:02:27 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[The term 'killing' appeared at +100% velocity from zero baseline alongside 'agency' and 'deployed'. In AI discourse, 'killing' typically appears in either disruption framing ('X is killing Y') or existential risk context. Combined with expert-tier silence on safety, this is worth disambiguating: if it's disruption narrative (e.g., 'AI agents killing SaaS'), it's market signal; if it's safety-adjacent, the absence of formal safety discourse makes it more concerning. Check the originating signal to classify.]]></description>
            <category>p2</category>
            <category>trend</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[[p2] HN 'meta' discussion — community reflexivity signal]]></title>
            <link>https://chrbailey.github.io/deeptrend/insights/2026-02-21.md</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://chrbailey.github.io/deeptrend/insights/2026-02-21#insight-10</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 08:02:27 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[HN Digest tagged one signal as 'meta' at +100% velocity from zero. Meta-discussion on HN (about HN itself, about tech culture, about AI content policy) historically clusters around community inflection points — the last major one preceded HN's AI content moderation changes. With 'deployed' and 'agency' also entering velocity, HN may be processing what AI agents mean for their community norms. Monitor next cycle for whether this expands — HN meta-discussion often predicts broader tech culture shifts by 2-4 weeks.]]></description>
            <category>p2</category>
            <category>divergence</category>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>